<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruby on Ivan Tkalin</title>
    <link>https://www.tkalin.com/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruby on Ivan Tkalin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ivan Tkalin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.tkalin.com/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails bug with polymorphic associations</title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/rails-bug-with-polymorphic-associations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/rails-bug-with-polymorphic-associations/</guid>
      <description>In general, I don&amp;rsquo;t like using polymorphic associations, because of inability to have a database-level integrity control and trickier eager loading. However, sometimes they look like a natural choice for certain cases in Ruby on Rails applications.
Recently, I faced a problem, which turned out to be a bug in how Rails handles negations with polymorphic associations. It took me some time to figure out what exactly was wrong, so I decided to share my experience here for future reference (mostly for myself).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to RSpec 3.x</title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/upgrading-to-rspec3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/upgrading-to-rspec3/</guid>
      <description>This short article is TL;DR of the talk: RSpec 3 and why I expect(you).to care by Jon Rowe. I picked 3 important recommendations out of this talk which I&amp;rsquo;m going to follow.
1. Use zero monkey patching mode This will completely disable all the monkey patching and will make RSpec less magical. Of course, it has a few consequences:
 DSL will not be exposed globally, so RSpec.describe must be used instead of describe etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating your Rails project codebase  with vim</title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/navigating-your-rails-project-codebase--with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/navigating-your-rails-project-codebase--with-vim/</guid>
      <description>When you work with source code, it is always nice to have the abilty to quickly jump to class/method definitions for either your own code or code from one of your ruby gems. This articles describes how to do this in vim with exuberant ctags, guard, and guard-ctags-bundler.
Tags  A tag is an identifier that appears in a &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; file. It is a sort of label that can be jumped to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>