<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on Ivan Tkalin</title>
    <link>https://www.tkalin.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Ivan Tkalin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ivan Tkalin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.tkalin.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Adobe Air and Elance Tracker on Ubuntu 13.10 (Saucy Salamander) 64 bit</title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/installing-adobe-air-and-elance-tracker-on-ubuntu-13-10-saucy-salamander-64-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/installing-adobe-air-and-elance-tracker-on-ubuntu-13-10-saucy-salamander-64-bit/</guid>
      <description>Update: Following instructions also work for Ubuntu 14.04 LTS Trusty Tahr 64 bit.
After upgrading to Ubuntu 13.10 (Saucy) 64 bits, I had troubles installing Adobe Air and Elance Tracker air application. None of the guides available online worked for me. The guide that I used to install it on Ubuntu 13.04 didn&amp;rsquo;t work either. I would be happy not to use this piece of crap by Adobe, but, unfortunately, Elance doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to build native tracker application for Linux, and I need it for my freelance work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using console vim as vim:// protocol handler in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/using-console-vim-as-vim/-protocol-handler-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/using-console-vim-as-vim/-protocol-handler-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Do you want your browser to launch console vim and open specified file on specified line when you click link like this: vim:///etc/hosts&amp;amp;line=10? This article will show how to register console vim as vim:// protocol handler in Ubuntu 11.10. Just follow these steps:
1. Create vim launcher script We&amp;rsquo;ll need small vim launcher script, which will handle vim://... uri. As a ruby programmer I wrote this script in Ruby (so it requires Ruby to be installed), but it can be rewritten to Perl/Python or even Bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadcasting your rhythmbox in ubuntu 11.10 </title>
      <link>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/broadcasting-your-rhythmbox-in-ubuntu-11.10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tkalin.com/blog_posts/broadcasting-your-rhythmbox-in-ubuntu-11.10/</guid>
      <description>Once I decided to setup my rhythmbox broadcasting into local network (so my wife or home media player could connect and listen), and didn&amp;rsquo;t find any comprehensive guide, so I decided to write my own when I managed to configure it.
I found a couple rhythmbox plugins for that, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me, so I stopped on icecast plus darkice.
Installing and configuring icecast Icecast is free server software for streaming multimedia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>